Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/scottgolder (LinkedIn) www.redlog.net (Personal)

Top Skills

Python

Management

Machine Learning

Certifications

Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning

Publications

Digital Footprints: Opportunities and Challenges for Online Social Research

Structural Predictors of Tie Formation in Twitter: Transitivity and Mutuality

Chapter 10: Twitter: Conversation, Entertainment, and Information, All in One Network! in In Analyzing Social Media Networks with NodeXL: Insights from a Connected World

Rhythms of Social Interaction: Messaging within a Massive Online Network

Usage Patterns of Collaborative Tagging Systems

Scott Golder

Data Science and Machine Learning executive Washington DC-Baltimore Area

Experience

The Home Depot Sr. Director of Data Science September 2022 - Present (8 months)

Washington, District of Columbia, United States

As leader of Online Data Science at The Home Depot, my teams are responsible for the core machine learning behind homedepot.com, a top-five eCommerce site.

We are responsible for search and recommendation capabilities, Visual AI (want to see what your room would like like with a new lamp or chair? Or if you painted it blue?), customer experience intelligence, and more.

I'm hiring data scientists at all levels, generalists as well as specialists in search, recommendations, NLP and CV.

Capital One

6 years 1 month

Senior Director, Data Science July 2021 - August 2022 (1 year 2 months)

Washington D.C. Metro Area

Data science and ML leader for a large, multidisciplinary (product, design, engineering, DS, delivery) product organization that is responsible for Capital One's flagship digital products, including our website, award-winning mobile app, intelligent assistant (chatbot) Eno, email, and beyond.

I led the DS/ML teams that deliver real-time, personalized, intelligent customer experiences, delighting a combined 50+ million customers each month and empowering them to manage their financial lives digitally.

Other things I worked on during my time at Capital One:

* Owning the maintenance and strategic direction of a key component of our on-site interview process that ensures our data scientists have top-notch statistical and communication skills

- * Hiring and leading the team that built the MVP of our enterprise-wide data intelligence / feature platform
- * Serving as Managing Data Steward for our Digital Products organization, responsible for establishing data quality metrics and practices, and providing first-line oversight and risk mitigation

Director, Data Science
July 2018 - July 2021 (3 years 1 month)

Sr. Manager, Data Science August 2016 - July 2018 (2 years) Washington D.C. Metro Area

Versive, now part of eSentire 6 years 5 months

Advisor

July 2016 - August 2018 (2 years 2 months)

Data Scientist and Head of Emerging Products Engineering July 2015 - July 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Data Scientist and Staff Sociologist April 2012 - July 2016 (4 years 4 months)

Google

Quantitative User Experience Intern
May 2012 - July 2012 (3 months)

Mountain View, California

Worked in Google Local on restaurant data.

Microsoft Research Intern May 2009 - August 2009 (4 months) Cambridge, MA

Projects included a web-based experiment on triadic closure in friendship ties in Twitter and an interview study with social media managers at Fortune 500 companies.

Hewlett Packard Researcher June 2005 - July 2008 (3 years 2 months)

Social Computing Lab (formerly Information Dynamics Lab). Carried out and published a wide variety of research projects, including laboratory experiments, software prototypes and large-scale data analyses of online social spaces.

IBM

Research Intern

June 2003 - August 2003 (3 months)

Cambridge, MA

Collaborative User Experience (CUE) Group. Conducted a study of reading behavior in email discussion lists.

Microsoft

Software Engineer Intern

June 2002 - August 2002 (3 months)

Redmond, Washington

Speech Components Group. Software Design Engineer Intern. Summer 2002. Created and expanded statistical language models for German speech recognition system.

Thinkingbytes Technology Software Engineer Intern June 2000 - 2002 (2 years)

Developed mobile database applications for Palm devices.

Education

Harvard University

AB, Linguistics, Computer Science · (1999 - 2003)

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

MS, Media Arts and Sciences · (2003 - 2005)

Cornell University

PhD, Sociology · (2008 - 2012)